Contact

aburmals1027@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/haribalaji-a-794343130 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Office Public Speaking C

Languages

Tamil (Native or Bilingual) Hindi (Elementary) English (Limited Working)

Haribalaji A

Secretary - SEDS INDIA, Innovation Engineer Trainee at Forge Accelerator

Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India

Summary

Experienced Student Secretary with a demonstrated history of working in College Clubs and National Student Chapter (SEDS). Skilled in C (Programming Language), C++, Teamwork, Teaching, and Public Speaking. Strong administrative professional with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused in Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation Engineering from Kumaraguru College of Technology.

Experience

FORGE Accelerator Innovation Engineer Trainee January 2019 - Present Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India

Innovation/Startup fellowship program is a 20-week, full-semester course called ProtoSem during which students are nurtured & guided to develop core technical concepts and key engineering skills and are transformed into 'Innovation Engineers'. We work as a team with students from different engineering/technical/science streams, towards designing, developing and testing an innovative tech enabled solution to solve a real-world problem (the Minimum Usable Prototype to test the technical feasibility and the commercial viability of the product innovation) sponsored by the industry, government, or social sector etc.

We solve real-world challenges using the tools enabled by hardware, software and computing technologies, and evolve as Graduate Innovation Engineers and fully rounded professionals with more balanced skills in the Innovation, Technology, and Engineering talent dimensions.

Graduate Innovation Engineers are creative problem-solvers, capable of building deployable/usable prototypes, selecting and applying technology to create cost effective solutions, and are aware of the tools and techniques of managing the process of innovation to mitigate and reduce risks. They innovate and design solutions by setting and achieving metrics in customer development & discovery, value-proposition validation, market definition & sizing, customer acquisition, revenue model & competition analysis.

SEDS India Secretary July 2018 - Present

Qubate
Joint Treasurer
July 2018 - Present
Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India

SEDS KCT Executive-PRO September 2017 - Present Coimbatore Area, India

Education

Kumaraguru College of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation

Engineering · (2016 - 2020)

Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan, Ajjanur High School · (2007 - 2016)